ifolor.net 2019-08-28

# Data Protection | ifolor

The ifolor team is delighted that you have chosen us to create your photo products. Your satisfaction is our top priority. Detailed below is our privacy policy, which we have drawn up so that you can be assured that we handle your photos and personal data correctly. This document explains what personal data (i.e., information related to identified or identifiable persons) we collect from your visit on our web sites and from your orders, and how these are processed and used. We also explain how we use [cookies](https://www.ifolor.com/data-protection#cookiepolicy).  

## Collection of personal data

Whenever you visit our web site, data relating to your access and data required for the operation of our user interfaces and the processing of your request will be temporarily stored on our web servers. This pertains to the connection data of your computer (IP address), the subpages you are visiting on our site, date and duration of your visit, recognition of the types of device, operating system and browser and the website or starting point from which you came to visit us.

Otherwise we only process data that you share with us while registering, placing an order or a request, and your image data and further information you send in to us for the processing of your orders. This data collection is not subject to a legal duty of notification with the authorities.

We collect and process such data only insofar as this serves the professional processing of your order and the maintenance of our customer relationship.

Apart from that we process anonymised information about how our visitors use our user interfaces; it helps us to enhance our services and the functions of our web sites, and to adapt them to your needs.

## Use and transfers of personal data

We treat your data confidentially as a matter of principle and do not pass them on to third party processors. However, we reserve the possibility to have the data processed by third parties in Switzerland or in EU countries, if so required for the operational processing of your orders. In such case, an adequate level of data protection will be ensured by compliance with the privacy protection laws applicable in Switzerland, the EU and in each such country, and by corresponding contracts with our suppliers.

So that reorders or potential complaints can be processed, your order information is held for up to 30 days before it is irrevocably deleted.

The electronic payment process (excluding invoice payments) takes place using our certified payment service provider, Datatrans AG in Zurich. Your payment data is sent directly from you to our payment service provider during payment and stored with them for a time-restricted period for the purposes of processing the payment and for potential complaints or refunds.

If you have subscribed to our newsletter, it is sent by our technical service provider, Selligent SA in Belgium, to whom we passed your data on when you registered for the newsletter. This transfer serves our legitimate interests in using an eye-catching, secure and user-friendly newsletter system. Acting on our instructions, Selligent SA uses this information for sending the newsletter and for carrying out a statistical, pseudonymised evaluation. You can unsubscribe from the newsletter at any time, either in writing or in the newsletter itself.

## Social Media Link

You may send us your image data for processing not only from your own devices but also through internet services such as Facebook, OneDrive and Picasa. Doing so, you do not grant us access to your login data for those services or to your other data placed in those services. The order software of ifolor is given access solely to your shared data and images and/or your public profile. These services will provide you with more detailed information about what data are thereby made accessible. Please also refer to these services’ privacy indications.  

## Google-Tag-Manager:

## Usage-based online advertising:

In this section, we would like to provide with extensive information on the topic of “usage-based online advertising”. Our website, or the website you were forwarded from, collects and processes your usage behaviour anonymously. This benefits you as a user, since you receive advertising which is more suited to your fields of interest, and because less randomly dispersed advertising is sent to you overall.

A cookie is saved on your computer to record your usage behaviour. This records information about your activity on this website (e.g. surfing behaviour, subpages visited on the internet service). All the usage data is stored with the use of a pseudonym, so that a personal identification is generally excluded. For data collection for the purpose of sending usage-based online advertising, we make use of the following tools:  
Adform, Affilinet, Bing, Facebook, Google, M-Pathy, Montemedia, Plista, Refined Ads, Romandie Network Conversion, Search Love, Selligent, Tradetracker, Trusted Shops

## Facebook Connect

Facebook Connect is a function by Facebook which allows Facebook users to sign in also to other websites, apps and services with their Facebook identity. This other service gains access to certain preferences and social connections stored in Facebook on which it can base its own offers. This follows the user’s settings on Facebook. You can find more information in the Facebook explanatory notes [Facebook](https://www.facebook.com/help/405977429438260/). Facebook can use data via users’ steps on these other services in order to recognise visitors of our website on its services, to be able to provide for the user’s interests and preferences. You can object to this form of advertising via the settings of your browser, which you can enter on the selection page of Digital Advertising Alliance [Digital Advertising Alliance](http://optout.aboutads.info/?c=2).

## Cookies

We seek to design our web presence as user friendly and efficient as possible. To this end, we apply cookies. You may decide yourself whether or not our software may load cookies onto your computer. You can configure your browser so that cookies will not be accepted, or only from certain web sites, or only after notice. Please observe, however, that the use of certain functions of our website may be restricted or disabled if you decline cookies from our web site. For a convenient experience we recommend a browser setting which accepts our cookies.

### Cookie policy

Cookies are small data files which are stored in the browser of your computer while it visits our web sites. Cookies support the functions of our service, by retaining your entries during a session or during an order process and by saving certain user settings. They also assist us with analysing the way our services are used, in order to design them as convenient and efficient as possible for our users.

We apply session cookies and permanent cookies. In addition, partner and affiliate cookies are employed. Session cookies remain stored only for the duration of a visit of our web sites, and are automatically deleted while closing the browser.

Permanent cookies remain on your computer until you delete them or their duration expires. They memorise anonymous information relating to users who repeatedly take access to one of our web sites. This helps us to offer optimised user guidance, and to recognise and distinguish one user from others, in order to maintain that user’s personal settings, simplify the user experience on the web site, and provide each user with customised contents and pages. These cookies are not designed to actually identify users. Such cookies are also implemented for purposes of anonymised web analytics, see

Partner and affiliate cookies are employed where a user takes access to our services via a platform of one of our partners (e.g. an advertising display). They serve for accounting with such partners, do not contain personal data of the user, and are deleted once the user registers on our user interface, or upon expiry of the pre-set duration.

The application of cookies can normally be avoided, restricted, or connected with a notice to the user by corresponding settings in your browser. The help manual of your browser will instruct you what to do. Please note, however: Some cookies are essential for the use of our web site, or of certain functions. If they are disabled, you may not be able to pass through the order process, and you may have to accept restrictions in display and user guidance. Please also note that there may be no possibility of disabling cookies when accessing our user interfaces by other means than through a browser, for instance, through mobile devices.

Below is a list of the session cookies and permanent cookies which we employ, and their functions:
